SREEKANTH CHIRIGIREDDY

+91-7299942515

Hyderabad 500049

SCM tools like GIT and Bitbucket.

chirigireddy.sreekanth@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Having 12 years of IT Experience as a Build, DevOps Engineer in the field of Software Configuration Management, Containerization and Cloud Platform.

Experience in configuring CICD pipelines using Azure DevOps. Having experience on using version control tool Git and its web repositories in Bitbucket for source code management system. Experienced in branching, tagging and maintaining the version across the environments using

Hands on experience in setting up and configuring Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery using tool like teamcity and Jenkins.

Hands on Experience with terraform to automate our infrastructure. Having experience on provisioning cloud and on on-premises resources as IAC using terraform.

Experience in Containerization tool like Docker and built Docker Images using Docker files. Experience on using Docker for successful setup of Dev & Test environment for Developers and Testers by using Docker Build & Compose.

Experience in Orchestrating containers across multiple hosts using kubernetes. Using kubernetes control and automate application deployments and updates.

Critical thinking DevOps Engineer with extensive understanding of high availability architecture and concepts. Purpose-driven professional with capacity to be strong team player plus work effectively independently.

Skills

- Configuration Management Tools: Chef and Ansible.
- Cloud Environment: Amazon Web Services, Azure DevOps
- Continuous Integration Tools: Jenkins and teamcity.
- Monitoring: ELK/Splunk.
- Deployment Tool: Docker.
- Version Control: GIT, SVN, Bitbucket.
- Scripting Languages: Powershell script, Bash.

- Application Server: Apache Tomcat, Nginx.
- · Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.
- Task Prioritization
- Custom Coding
- Performance Management
- · Maintenance and Troubleshooting

Work History

CLOUD DEVOPS ENGINEER. 11/2022 - Current Bank Of America, Hyderabad, TG

- Creating terraform modules and publish it terraform registry and provisioning infrastructure using the modules.
- Automating Infrastructure using Terraform and running through the CI pipeline.
- · Creating the Ansible playbook's for application deployments and creating templates for the same.
- Support DevOps process improvements and CI/CD delivery. Hardening the infrastructure,

Cloud migrations and digital transformations.

- Creating the templates for application deployments and handling the releases using XL Release.
- I Discuss and recommend implementing a new DevOps tool that is fits for our organization's requirements.
- Worked with cross-functional design teams to create software solutions that improved overall functionality and performance.
- Monitored automated build and continuous software integration process to drive build/release failure resolution.

DEVOPS ENGINEER, 05/2020 - 11/2022

Likewize, Chennai, TN

- Migrated existing CICD setup from TFS to Azure DevOps.
- Support DevOps process improvements and CI/CD delivery. Hardening the infrastructure, Cloud migrations and digital transformations.
- Configuring CI/CD pipelines and deploying the application on SIT/UAT and production servers.
- Involved in configuring CI/CD pipeline using Azure DevOps for AWS based Serverless.
- Design for hosting Mobile Apps Gateway Serverless application built and deployed as single stack using Cloud Formation template.

BUILD & DEVOPS ENGINEER, 12/2011 - 04/2020

Navis India Technologies, Chennai, TN

DevOps Engineer:

- Developing Chef Cookbooks and Dockerfile for different scenarios to manage the infrastructure and integrating with CI / CD (Jenkins).
- Used configuration management tools like **Chef** to deploy consistent infrastructure code across multiple environments.
- Developed Chef Cookbooks and Roles to automate the infrastructure.
- Bootstrapped a client machine in Chef to bring the node server under chef control.
- Used **Chef Cookbooks** and Shell scripts to automate the deployment process in to the Linux environment.
- Responsible for installing **Jenkins** master and slave nodes.
- Configure, Monitor and Automate Amazon Web Services.
- Creating and Managing the Amazon Web Services using EC2, Elastic IP's, RDS, EBS, VPC, ELB, Auto-Scaling, AMI, Cloud Watch, and Security groups on AWS
- Creating **S3 buckets** and also managing policies for S3 buckets and Utilized S3 bucket for storage and backup on AWS.
- Worked on infrastructure with **Docker Containerization**.
- Assisted end-to-end release process from the planning of release content through to actual release deployment to production.
- Developed and implemented software release management strategies for various applications according to Agile process.
- Good experience in working with a team together to deliver best outputs in given time frames.
- Supported the application/Cookbooks in production and worked closely with off-shore teams.

Build Engineer:

- Handling Build and Release activities.
- Responsible for Daily builds, Continuous build and patch builds.
- Performing Smoke/Sanitary test on the application.

- Writing Build.xml files as per project requirements.
- Creating Installers using Install Anywhere tool.
- On-going maintenance/improvements for installers.
- Checking whether installers are working fine in each build.
- Take ownership of the installers; design, function, features, etc.

Education

Master Of Science

Anna University - Chennai, TN, 06/2009

Master of computer applications, Anna University Chennai, 2009

Locations

Plot No:977, Miyapur, Hyderabad, 500049

Communication Address

Plot No:977, Miyapur, Hyderabad, 500049

Personal Information

• Date of Birth: 04/10/1985

• Marital Status: Married

Disclaimer

I hereby declare that the above furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge.